Oliver Switzer

(i) www.oliverswitzer.com



About me

With 7 years of experience working with various server and client-side languages, I am looking to work with startups or large companies that are making a social, creative or environmental impact using technology. I enjoy learning from and mentoring other engineers through pairing, as well as advocating for extreme programming (XP) practices like test driven development and delivering value-proven software in short iterations. I also am a big proponent of Domain Driven Design and studying object oriented principles. With that said, I am always looking to learn new languages and practices and continue expanding my area of expertise.



Technical Skills

| Ruby | Rails | Kotlin | Java | Elixir | nod | e.js | Pyth | non | GraphQ | L | ES6 | Тур | eScript |
|-------------|-------|--------|-------|--------|------|-------|------|------|--------|-----|----------|------|---------|
| React | Redux | HTML | .5 CS | SS3 | SASS | Apoll | 0 | Post | gresQL | Ela | asticsea | ırch | EC2 |
| S3 Redshift | | Angula | r | | | | | | | | | | |



Work experience

06/2018 - 05/2020 Brooklyn, United States

Senior Software Engineer Kickstarter

Collaborated with product and design to break down work for myself and teammates, mentored other engineers and built out critical infrastructure

- Planned and implemented Kickstarter's new signup and checkout experience that increased completed checkouts by 4%, roughly \$1M in annual revenue
- Supported our iOS and Android native app teams through building out APIs and building cross-platform features
- Built out scalable ETL process for replicating and sanitizing our production payments database
- Developed support tools to improve communication during site outages, as well as a UI that aggregates and categorizes site incidents to find trends

08/2015 - 05/2018 Brooklyn, NY, **United States**

Software Engineer Pivotal

Acted as engineering lead on multiple projects, involving conveying core domain to rest of team, scheduling one-on-ones with individual team members and facilitating communication between my development team and client stakeholders

· Worked in multiple product contexts (finance, health care, charity,



education), to deliver full-stack features

- Actively participated in and helped plan user research sessions, as well as technical discovery into new product domains
- Helped identify what new client projects and employees Pivotal will take on
- Facilitate weekly retrospectives, iteration planning meetings and officewide discussions about core XP/LEAN/Agile practices and values

08/2014 – 06/2015 Brooklyn, NY, United States

Software Engineer littleBits

Third engineering hire; hit the ground running with small balanced team to deliver both front and back end feature work

- Created a crowdsourcing voting app, that uses state machine logic to track circuit ideas that are voted upon and curated
- Helped start NYC's first official React Meetup hosted at the littleBits office
- Worked with React to create first interactive littleBits circuit simulator
- Built out RESTful mobile app API endpoints
- Increased on site performance by 17% using Redis-backed view caching

04/2014 – 07/2014 Brooklyn, NY, United States

Software Engineer HowAboutWe

Implemented full stack features for product team in charge of "HowAboutWe for singles" application

- Worked in Rails stack with Backbone/SASS/HAML, and TDD (RSpec & Capybara) when writing code for both front and back-end site functionality in
- Worked with extensive Memcached-based caching system
- Created models that implement worker queues for sending SMS to users using Twilio API



Education

02/2014 – 06/2014 Brooklyn, NY

09/2009 – 05/2013 Annandale-on-Hudson, NY

, United States

Software Engineering The Flatiron School

Physics Bard College

• Received a full-ride Distinguished Scientist Scholarship (DSS)



Hobbies



Cooking



Snowboarding



Surfing & Swimming



Ping pong



Hiking



Hockey



Songwriting



Traveling